Zach Zhong

z1zhong@ucsd.edu | 626-678-7725 | Linkdin | Github

SUMMARY

Third year undergraduate at UCSD experienced in mobile/web development both as a full stack developer and a leader in startup projects using React.JS, React Native, and deployment and design of databases / API services. Familiar with fundamentals of computer architecture/system/network/security as well as machine learning.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego

B.S. in Computer Science

• IDEA Scholar @ Jacob School of Engineering

Major GPA: 3.837

CSE 100 - Advance Data Structure, CSE 101 - Design/Analysis of Algorithm; CSE 132A - Database Management Principles; CSE 151B - Deep Learning; CSE 158 - Recommender System; CSE 120 Operating Systems; CSE 123 Computer Network; CSE 127 Computer Security; CSE 132B - Database System Implementation; CSE 135 - Online Database Analytics Applications

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

CutiePet Tech Lead / Full Stack Developer

September 2021 - Present

September 2020 - June 2024

- Responsible for onboarding new tech members and closely collaborating with project managers and designers following agile principles.
- Built the frontend for onboarding, integration login/sign up authentication through AWS Cognito, profile and messaging using React
 Native utilizing common frontend practices such as Typescript, hooks, forms, contexts while building reusable components.
- Built backend RESTFUL API with AWS Lambda, deploying the serverless is though AWS API Gateway
- Integrated **websocket** to enable chat functionality in the frontend.
- Integrated backend service connecting to MongolDB with Node.JS.
- Implemented optimization techniques such as image caching and pre-loading to improve load times images by 50% and ensure a smoother user experience in the frontend.

University of California, San Diego

March 2023 - June 2023

Computer Science and Engineering(CSE) Tutor

- Worked under Professor Sicun Gao for class CSE 150B: AI: Search and Optimization which includes topics such as Adversarial/Classical Search, Reinforcement Learning, Constraints Solving.
- Assisted the class of 300+ students and answered questions through discussions and office hours.
- Presented and prepared slides on reinforcement learning topics Monte Carlo Tree Search for podcasting.
- Graded homework assignments and provided feedback.

PROJECT

Surfn

- Built profile carousel and onboarding page logics web application with **Next.JS**.
- Created landing page for website.
- Transplanted web version onto **React Native** and matinted functionality/components.
- Develop reusable components with **React.JS** and invoke API calls to the **Starlette** backend.

Steam Game Data Analytics Git Repo

- Gathered using the steam api and scraped the rest of the missing data and processed them with **pandas** and **numpy in python**.
- Evaluated different heuristics functions and categorization techniques before applying different machine learning models.
- Deployed a different logisticRegression / SGD / SVM classifier to using **sklearn** library.
- Built and fine tuned a deep learning model using **pytorch** to achieve 50% accuracy in the categorization of playtime based on profile.

South Hills Countdown Git Repo

- Led and guided a team of students in developing a school mobile app using Xamarin.Forms, written with C#, and designing interface Xaml MVC design pattern.
- Integration with Google Firebase and push notification with realtime database.
- Added support for mac by building a menu bar application using **AppKit**.
- Served over 1000+ students and teachers at the high school of class times and upcoming events.

TritonLink132B Git Repo

- Design relational schema for PostGresSQL modeling classes, students, departments, sections, faculty, etc of a school's backend system, implementing appropriate constraints and adhering design to 3NF.
- Deployed databases and frontend with Apache Tomcat powered by JSP(Java Server Pages).
- Built frontend with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and backend with Java Servlet.
- Build pure SQL queries that allow a student to make a decision to report such a degree audit, professor to schedule courses without conflicts.

SKILLS

- **Tech Stacks:** React.JS, Expo, Xcode, Android Studio, Xamarin Forms, Firebase, SQL, MongolDB, AWS S3, AWS Lambda, AWS Cognito, Azure function, Serverless, JUnitTest, Postman, Node.JS, Express.js, Django, JSP, Apache Tomcat
- Language and Tools: Git, Docker, DigitalOcean, AWS, Unix, C, C#, C++, Python, Javascript, Typescript, Java, PHP
- **Systems**: Verilog, SystemVerilog, Assembly, ARM